Jared Ryan

jryantennis@gmail.com | (559) 348-3595 | jaredryanwork.space | github.com/jaredryan

Summary

Full stack software engineer specializing in React.js and Node.js. Front end lead of the user and role management service in IBM's data and AI analytics platform. Open to relocation.

Skills: JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, SQL, Python, Java, Ruby

Experience

IBM, Cloud Pak for Data Software Developer II

San Jose, CA Apr 2019 - Present

- Led front end development and co-lead for backend development in React.js and Node respectively for user and role management for Cloud Pak for Data, a data and AI analytics platform
- Co-created conceptual models and user flows with design, providing guidance on attributes and relationships between users, roles, permissions, and groups
- Architected technical solutions with product and backend lead, considering security, performance, sizing, business value, and usability
- Led features on backend: adding a new audit module, integrating our login process with other internal products, giving us the capability to support multiple LDAP configurations
- Mentored and led product innovations teams, leading to 3 publications

IBM, AppID Software Developer I

Austin, TX

Jun 2018 - Mar 2019

- Junior developer on AppID, which helps developers easily add security to their apps
- Prototyped a fullstack application in React, Node, and Python showcasing all uses of ApplD, and was leveraged for sales pitches and demos
- Adapted to multiple technologies to quickly debug issues: OAuth, OpenID, Node, Angular, Java, Android, Swift, Kubernetes, Docker, Jenkins, Github, Zenhub

Negotiation and Team Resources Institute Web Developer

Berkeley, CA Apr 2018 - Present

- Sole developer on a web app for collecting, grading, and anonymizing peer feedback, which has been used by 600 students, across 7 schools, generating 6K evaluations
- Collaborated with UC Berkeley professor to define product requirements and designs
- Addressed client and user issues through discussion, collaboration, then implementation
- Created data visualizations to show grades against class benchmarks

Site: https://negotiationfeedback.herokuapp.com

Education

UC Berkeley College of Engineering B.S. Bioengineering, Computer Science emphasis

Dec 2017